Software Engineer

Hard Skills

Programming Languages: Java, C++, C#, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, NodeJS, React, and MongoDB

Math: Calculus 1, 2, and 3 along with Linear Algebra

Other: Data structures, databases, version control, computer vision, automation with trajectory planning, interfacing with APIs, libraries, and motors/sensors, Android app development, PID control

Soft Skills

- Working collaboratively in software development
- Teaching, lesson planning, written and oral communication
- Leadership, conflict resolution
- Critical thinking, problem-solving, and attention to detail

Volunteer Work

I have spent hundreds of hours volunteering at FIRST Robotics competitions, spreading my passion for STEM to younger students. I also worked with my FRC Robotics team to attend outreach events at museums and fairs to share my love of STEM to even more people.

Student at the University of Washington's Paul G. Allen School of Computer Science. Multiple years of experience in Robotics, Web Development, and

Education

Henry M. Jackson High School

Sep 2019 – June 2023

High School Diploma, Valedictorian (GPA: 4.0) Member of FRC Team 2910

Everett Community College (Running Start) Sep 2021 – June 2023

Associate in Art and Science, President's Distinction (GPA: 4.0)

Awards

- FRC Autonomous Award Sponsored by Ford (twice in 2022, once in 2023)
- 2023 Indiana Robotics Invitational Scholar, IRI Host Teams Scholarship
- AP Scholar, AP Scholar with Honor

Experience

Computer Science Tutor – Coding With Kids Aug 2021 – April 2023

At this at Coding With Kids premier coding academy, I tutored young children in the basics of computer programming in languages like Scratch and Python.

Lead Software Developer – FRC Team 2910 Sept 2021 – July 2023

In High School, I was a member of a world-class robotics team. We finished 3rd place in the world in 2022 and won over 10 major competitions over these two years. On this team, I wrote award-winning autonomous code and had the opportunity to work closely with mentors who are industry experts (Microsoft, Boeing, etc.). I picked up skills like computer vision, autonomous motion and trajectory planning, PID control, and even Android app development.